Mr S SUTHAKARAN

Mobile: 82961337

E-mail: tssutha@gmail.com Availability: 2Months Notice

Career Objectives:

Accomplished, self-motivated and versatile IT professional with well-developed software development and consultation skills combined with strong interpersonal and industry experience, seeks the next big career challenge and an opportunity to apply his knowledge and expertise on a larger scale.

Specialties:

Automation Software for Semiconductor Industry, SECS/GEM Application, Laser Marking Software, Wire Bonder Application, Data Analysis, System Analysis and Design

Recent Interest:

Web and Mobile App Development, Cloud Computing, Trading Platform Development

Technical Skills:s

Programming Languages: C/C++, MFC, STL, C#, XAML, Python, MySQL, VB6, VBA, UML, XML,

HTML, CSS, JavaScripts

Frameworks: Win Forms, WPF, ADO.NET, LINQ2SQL, WebPy, KlockWork, Heroku

Programming Paradigms: Agile Development, Object Oriented Programming and Design, SOA, Model

Driven Development, Design Patterns

OS & Applications: Windows, Linux, MS Office, GnuPlot, VideoCAD and Adobe Photoshop

Development Environment: Eclipse, Visual Studios, MS SQL Servers

Version Control Systems: SVN, PVCS, Git, BitBucket

Professional Work Experience

Oct 2010 – Present Software Engineer ASM Technology Singapore Ptd Ltd.

Responsible for delivering software solutions on time with top quality for client engagements. Manage project deliverables, schedule and reporting on multiple development initiatives. Work with Process Analysts and Field Engineers to generate new requirements. Researched, Developed and presented new software modules and support tools to senior management. Experienced in working onsite with major semiconductor manufactures.

- Design and Developed SECS/GEM communication module, successfully deployed at Texas Instruments Production Lines.
- Design and Developed an API which reduce the wire bonder looping set up time to few minutes from hours (75% to 90%). Few button clicks will do the job for the user expectation.
- Successfully developed many mathematical models and algorithms for wire bonder solutions, which involved a lots of data analysis using MatLab and GnuPlot. Real Time Looping Motion Collision Detection, Looping Recipe Ranking and Forward Feed Control Error handling...etc.
- Delivered many support software tools for Research and Development.
- Delivered many software application prototypes for product development in short periods.
- Lead a Team of Two through the complete life cycle of a project to provide an intelligent help system for wire bonder machine which reduce the product training for the end user.
- Provide Training for End User about newly developed features.

Jan 2008 – Jan 2009 Software Engineer, Excel Technology Lanka (pvt) Ltd

Responsible for designing and constructing features for Laser Marking application. Constructed and presented requirement specifications and straining materials for new customers, developers and managers.

- Developed Requirement specification and Functional Design Specification documents for the new user requirements and help QA team to developed test cases based on the specification before start the implementations.
- Greatly involved in UX design and implementation. Took the responsibility to migrate the older UX
 to latest concept using latest Microsoft technologies and third party tools and successfully completed
 within the deadline.
- Successfully achieved many redesigning and restructuring software modules of the legacy system in order to scale up the system to meet ever increasing demands.
- Successfully Developed a COM component to enable the remote access to Laser Marking Machines.
- Attended project and clients meetings and involved in requirements gathering and knowledge transferring sessions.

2006 Feb- 2006 July s<u>Trainee Electrical Engineer</u>, IE Techniques Groups.

- Worked with R&D team to carry out testing and performance analysis of electronic and electrical products.
- Worked with a team of 4 which successfully re-designed a TV antenna booster for performance tuning.
- Produced and presented weekly and monthly reports to management and university.

Education

2009-2010	Distinction in MSc Advanced Software Engineering , University of Leicester, UK.
2003-2007	2:1 in BSc Electrical Engineering (Hons) , University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka
2004-2006	Professional Graduate Diploma in IT, British Computer Society, UK
1994-2002	Secondary Education, Hartley College, Sri Lanka GCSE A/L Mathematics A, Physics A, Chemistry B

Other achievements

- Associate member of British Computer Society, [AMBCS]
- Treasure of Tamil Literary Association, University of Moratuwa [2006-2007]
- Member of senior prefect board.
- Member of Under 17 Football Team [1997-1999]

References: Available on Request